Finding Aid for Board of Regents (University of Michigan)agendas
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Board of Regents (University of Michigan) agendas 1996-(ongoing}
University of Michigan. Board of Regents.
32 linear feet.
0582 Bimu B2 2
The Board of Regents is the governing body of the University of Michigan. The records include agendas for the Regents meetings, with included exhibits, and reports on university finances, promotions, and degree confirmations.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Agenda books are received immediately following each meeting of the Board of Regents (Donor no. 5932 ).
The record group is open without restriction.
See the finding aid for Board of Regents (University of Michigan), Records for a historical note on the Board of Regents.
Since 1996 the archives has been receiving agenda books immediately following each meeting of the Board of Regents. These agendas are published volumes which serve as a public record of the meetings. They contain detailed agendas for each meeting as well as some exhibits from the meetings and reports on university finances, promotions, and degree confirmations. Those agenda books comprise this collection.
These records include various items: Regents communications, reports, recommendations, and other documents presented to the Regents for consideration at their meetings. They form the most complete record of the Regents' actions. As the official governing body of the university, the Regents deal with virtually every aspect of university policy and life. The records of the Regents reflect this broad range of interests and authority. But while the documentation is wide-ranging, it is not continuous. Certain types of records are continually before the Regents, particularly information regarding salaries, leaves of absence, appointments to faculty positions, and formal approval of degrees conferred upon students. More often, however, the Regents are presented with a specific problem and asked to resolve it through the creation of policy. After the creation and successful implementation of a policy, the situation which caused the issue to arise is usually no longer a matter of Regental concern. The Regents' records reflect this pattern of action. Issues arise, are resolved, and then are supplanted by new concerns.
The Proceedings of the Board of Regents (1837- ) are accessible online at the following URL: < http://www.hti.umich.edu/u/umregproc/ >
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Board of Regents.; University of Michigan--Administration
- Regents Agendas
  - March 1996-July 1996 (Box 1)
  - September 1996-March 1997 (Box 2)
  - April 1997-July 1997 (Box 3)
  - August 1997-March 1998 (Box 4)
  - April 1998-September 1998 (Box 5)
  - October 1998-April 1999 (Box 6)
  - May 1999-October 1999 (Box 7)
  - November 1999-May 2000 (Box 8)
  - June 2000-November 2000 (Box 9)
  - December 2000 – July 2001 (Box 10)
  - September 2001 – March 2002 (Box 11)
  - April 2002 – September 2002 (Box 12)
  - September 2002-April 2003 (Box 13)
  - May 2003-November 2003 (Box 14)
  - December 2003-July 2004 (Box 15)
  - October 2004-April 2005 (Box 16)
  - May 2005-September 2005 (Box 17)
  - October 2005-March 2006 (Box 18)
  - April 2006-September 2006 (Box 19)
  - October 2006-April 2007 (Box 20)
  - May 2007-September 2007 (Box 21)
  - October 2007-April 2008 (Box 22)
  - May 2008-December 2008 (Box 23)
    (includes 2008 End of Year Report)
  - January 2009-October 2009 (Box 24)
  - November 2009-June 2010 (Box 25)
  - July 2010-February 2011 (Box 26)
  - March 2011-October 2011 (Box 27)
  - November 2011-September 2012 (Box 28)
  - October 2012-May 2013 (Box 29)
  - June 2013--February 2013 (Box 30)
  - March 2014--October 2014 (Box 31)
  - November 2014-- (Box 32)
Related Material
The official set of Board of Regents records, inducing the original exhibits and agenda as maintained by the Secretary of the University, are transferred to the custody of the archives on a fixed twenty-five year schedule (e.g., the "official" agendas and exhibits for 1980 Regents meetings are scheduled for transfer to the archives in 2005). For the record group containing the original exhibits, see the separate record group and finding aid for University of Michigan. Board of Regents (call no. 8722 Bimu B2 2).